JOHN OSAMEDE OSARETIN

LUTON, UNITED KINGDOM | +44 07733678077 | www.linkedin.com/in/johnosamedeosaretin | osaretinjohn2000@gmail.com

PROFILE

John Osaretin is an ardent IT professional offering an oriented approach with experience in Web and Mobile design, Front-end development, Back-end development, Networking, Telecommunication, and Identity services. He is a postgraduate student at The University of Bedfordshire, where he is studying software engineering and applications.

John has specialized in a customer support environment, and he is a strong technical resource for teams regarding case reviews, troubleshooting, service management, and effective customer interaction. He is an individual with great working experience on several IT Projects who is motivated, dependable, and adaptable. He has experience and exposure working on IT projects in environments with a variety of cultures, which have outstanding clients, internal and external personnel, and student involvement. He possesses extensive technical expertise and the ability to solve problems in any workplace using both practical and research-based methods. He can work well with others, pays close attention to detail, and is not afraid to welcome change.

John is a terrific asset to any organization because of his positive outlook and can-do attitude.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages and Frameworks: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Python, C#, ASP.Net, ASP.Net MVC, Django.
- Database: MS SQL Server (or other RDMS) Operating
- Version Control: GIT, GitHub, Subversion.
- Systems: Linux, Windows Server
- Network: LAN, WAN, VPN, Hub-Spoke, Cisco
- Platforms: Web flow, Figma, Visual Studio Code, Sublime Text.
- Qualifications: UI/UX Design, CAD, AutoCAD, Project Management, Technical problem-solving, Operation monitoring, Information collection and analysis, Teamwork, Competence in the use of MS Office Suite.

CERTIFICATIONS:

- ✓ The Complete Web Developer Nanodegree (Udemy)
- ✓ The Complete Web Designer Nanodegree (Udemy)
- ✓ HTML5 and CSS3 Fundamentals
- ✓ Introduction to Python
- ✓ JavaScript Essentials

Areas of interest: Technology, UI/UX, Web development, Mobile app development, Software Testing, security, DevOps, Networking, Data Analysis, Project Management, IT Consultancy, Information systems management, IT Support Management, Social Media Management, Product Management, Digital Services.

EDUCATION

University of Bedfordshire

Luton, Bedfordshire.

Candidate for Master of Science in Software Engineering 03/2022 – Present.

- Contributed to 2 high-quality, reliable projects as a Full-stack Software Engineer, which resulted in two finished projects for two external projects with an impact on the increasing view of their startups.
- One finished internal project as the developer of the whole project using C#, ASP.NET Core Razor Pages and ASP.NET Core MVC.
- Developed and documented the building of an application in an Agile team using software development techniques and applying open-source frameworks.
- Led a group of 10 as the Project Manager in the research on emerging technologies to replace Passwords
- Started a social Media campaign to raise awareness for the research carried out above.

Benson Idahosa University

Benin city, Nigeria.

Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical and Electronics Engineering First Class Honours

2016-2021.

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT SUPPORT/ PROGRAM COORDINATOR | 02/2020 - 09/2020 National Television Authority

Abuja, Nigeria

- Engaged with customers to understand and meet their needs so as to maximize their user experience
- Developed network resources, administered, and prepared IP address programs, and educated support staff to offer Tier I service to end customers.
- Assisted Client with general support for hardware, peripherals, network connections and external software.
- Administered and prepared programs for IP addresses, developed network resources and trained support personnel to provide Tier 1 support to end users.

INTERN ENGINEER | 06/2018 - 08/2019

Abuja, Nigeria

Independent National Electoral Commission

- Completed tasks efficiently and timely, as instructed by engineering managers.
- Gained practical experience by visiting clients to fix, replace or upgrade systems.
- Managed all on-site installation, repair, maintenance and test tasks.
- Stayed in line with health and safety guidelines by wearing required Personal Protective Equipment (PPE).
- Observed multiple strategies and techniques for engineering tasks such as construction, repairing and maintenance.
- Closely monitored engineers complete various tasks to obtain better understanding of best practices.
- Cultivated excellent working relationships with other engineers by proactively assisting in difficult engineering tasks.

PROFESSIONAL STRENGTH

- Effective Communication
- Management and Leadership skills

- Teamwork
- Problem Solving
- Logical and Ethical thinking.